Guide to the Alice Kahn Ladas papers,1943-2013.
Ladas, Alice Kahn papers, 1943-2013
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alice Kahn Ladas papers, 1943-2013.
7728
Alice Kahn Ladas
0.2 cubic feet
Speeches, correspondence, pamphlets, articles and newspaper clippings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alice Kahn Ladas speeches and articles, correspondence, memos, pamphlets, and clippings.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
A sexual liberation activist who was instrumental in establishing Lamaze education in the U.S. and promoting breastfeeding and who published a NEW YORK TIMES bestseller, "The G Spot and Other Discoveries About Human Sexuality," with Beverly Whipple and John D. Perry in 1982.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Alice Kahn Ladas speeches and articles, correspondence, memos, pamphlets, and clippings. Includes a 1943 memo detailing her reasons for wanting an internship with the Fair Employment Practices Commission and with a U.S. Congressperson, a 1945 letter of thanks from employees of the U.S. Patent Office for her assistance getting their positions upgraded, a 1951 letter from Eva Reich of the Wilhelm Reich Foundation, notes about a meeting with Eleanor Roosevelt, and a 1991 letter to friends. Pamphlets and clippings contain her writing on breast feeding, sexuality and women's liberation, and bioenergetic analysis. Included is the program from a speech on “The Sexual Revolution: Phase Two” given March 14, 2004 at the New York Society for Ethical Culture, a society she has been involved with since childhood.
Also, an issue of Balanced Living containing an article by Alice Hammarth, "Breast Feeding and Bottle Feeding Compared" (October 1960); and an issue of The USA Body Psychotherapy Journal containing an article by Alice Kahn Ladas, "An Appreciation of Alexander Lowen" (2008).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ladas, Alice Kahn.; La Leche League International.
Subjects:
Bioenergetics.; Breastfeeding.; Female orgasm.; G spot.; Sex.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection
CONTAINER LIST
- Photo, Alice Kahn Ladas (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, memos, 1943-2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- News stories about Alice Kahn Ladas, 1972, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- NYICOP brochure (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Writings on breastfeeding, circa 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Writings on La Leche League (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Women and Bioenergetic Analysis," "Using Goals in Bioenergetic Analysis", 1981, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Working With the Body", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "The G Spot Revisited", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Writings on orgasm and sexual liberation, 2004, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Relating Exercises" (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Writings, articles and speeches, 1976-2008 (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
- Issue of Balanced Living with article by Alice Hammarth, "Breast Feeding and Bottle Feeding Compared", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Issue of The USA Body Psychotherapy Journal with article by Alice Kahn Ladas, "An Appreciation of Alexander Lowen", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 17)